



#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I have a thirst for knowledge and experience. My passions have varied over time, but my desire to learn is consistent. This allows me to effectively contribute when working with others, and provides me with continued motivation when working alone.

The combination of my strong technical theory and my appreciation for aesthetics has provided the foundation of my career path, fueling my desire to bridge the gap between functional technology and aesthetic design.

## **EDUCATION**

- School of Visual Arts Sept 2009 Jan 2013 Bachelors of Fine Arts − 3.5 GPA Graphic Design New York, New York
- Northeastern Univeristy Sept 2003 May 2005
  Creative Writing & Journalism
  Boston, Massachusetts
- School of Audio Engineering Nov 2006 May 2007 Audio Engineering & Digital Production New York, New York

### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

## 1. DEVELOPMENT

HTML5 & CSS3 (SASS)
JavaScript & jQuery
Preprocessors (Gulp)
MVC Frameworks (React)
Responsive Design
Cross-Browser Practices
SEO Best Practices



2. DESIGN

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Sketch, InVision (Zeplin)



- a. 638 Grand St. Apt. 2 Brooklyn, NY 11211
- t. 203 644 4827
- e. info@adamfratino.com
- w. github.com/88mpg codepen.io/88mpg

## PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE



My immediate employment objective is to be a front-end web developer for an innovative company that embraces both cutting-edge technology and lasting aesthetics.

I would thrive as a member of a team that values communication and collaboration when working towards a common goal.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

The Barbarian Group August 2014 - Present
Design Technologist, New York City

Joined a team of three to become lead on a team of five. Duties included full-stack development on larger incremental projects, creating custom boilerplates for our team to use, major bug fixes, and building new global properties for an enterprise electronics retailer. As my role has grown, I've also become responsible for team resourcing, internal documentation, Jira management, and project scoping.

Global Point New York Sept 2013 - June 2014
Senior Web Developer, New York City

Sole developer, full-stack web development for a small creative agency. Typical process included client interfacing, translating flat artwork into functional wireframes, full development, cross-browser testing, production setup and deployment.

Freelance Web Development Apr 2008 - July 2013

Various full-stack projects ranging from small- and medium-sized businesses to independent creatives. Includes custom Wordpress themes and plugins and static builds.

MacGuffin & Assembly Films Aug 2010 - Sept 2013
Production Assistant and Digital Specialist, New York City
Full-time PA work while I attended SVA. Hardest job ever.

# **REFERENCES**

Both professional and personal references upon request.

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Development samples: 88MPG on Github & CodePen
Creative & design portfolio: adamfratino.com



